Please start performing our live attacks, scanning networks and developing payloads, it's
very important that we understand one thing clearly, for hacking its powerful knowledge
and with that power comes to responsibilities too.
Of course, which I have designed that teaches you how real world cyber attacks happen because
most of the tools and commands and scripts that we have used in this course that was used
by multiple detectors in various incidents across the globe.
So, but the goal is not to break the law, it's to understand how attack works so that you
can different systems strengthen networks and protect data.
So, what exactly is ethical hacking?
Ethical hacking means testing system, networks and application with permission from the
organization or the end user to find vulnerabilities before malicious hackers exploit them.
You use the same tool in the course and techniques that attackers use, but you propose
the opposite way to help organizations to fix, weakness and improve their security poster.
So, that's the one thing what separates a cyber security professional from cyber criminal.
So, everything you learn in this course should be practiced only in the controlled lab
environment.
The one you set up on your own computer using virtual box and isolated system.
So, you must never perform scans, exploits or malware execution on public networks website
or system that you don't own or you don't have an access, you don't have a right permission
or two tests.
If you want to rent some test to take permission from the company, take permission from
the website owners, take appropriate necessary agreements and then perform a test.
So, if you did something, it could violate a cyber security loss like computer misuse
act, CFA or your local country, whatever it supports, you are misleading the IT regulations
and that could lead a serious legal action.
Many people underestimate how serious this can be, even a simple port scan on a company
server, sometime it costs a big problem because it is also called as an unauthorized access
in many countries.
As a cyber security professionals, our duty is to act responsibly, respect privacy and
use of a skill to protect, not to exploit, remember every attack the performance scores
is only for an educational purpose.
So, please perform all the attacks which we have covered in the private and isolated networks.
Also, please execute all the tools which we have created in this course.
If you are creating some tools, please test it in the isolated network.
So, don't misuse that and don't use it in the other organizations or any government
organizations.
So, in cyber security, your reputation is everything, employers, client and even government
agencies look for look for professionals, cyber security professionals who are ethical
trust worthy and compliant.
So, always get written permission before testing a network or system that is not yours,
respect or confidentiality, never share, exploit, code through anyone, anywhere in any public
platforms.
So, always remember one thing, the true hackers mindset is about curiosity, creativity and
improvement not destruction.
So, we are not going to distract any organization across the globe, but we our aim is to protect
and prevent the cyber attacks that was happening in the organization.
So, by this following ethical guidelines, you will build the mindset of a true cyber
security professionals, someone who understand the system deeply and uses that knowledge
to make the digital world safer.
So, as far as we go forward with practical labs, always stay with ethical and legal boundaries
now that you know how to learn safely, let's move on setting up a lab environment in the
next sections and we will start exploring the world of offensive and defensive security
in the course.
So, again and again which I am saying, so don't misuse the tools or techniques what we covered
in this course because I have used all the commands that was previously executed by some
kind of threat actors across the globe against multiple organizations.
Thank you for watching this video, so we will connect you in the next section.
Thank you.